all right it's like committed to doing
this by 10 o'clock and I have a call at
9:00 and I wanted to get this done
beforehand I was also watching the good
place this morning while I was getting
my kid ready for school and so there's
gonna be spoiler alerts so if you
haven't caught up if you don't know
what's going on in a good place then
maybe don't watch this if you care but
in the previous episode or the episode I
just watched they talked about how this
is if you don't know the good place they
there's a it's a sitcom where people get
taken to what I think is heaven it turns
out to be hell and it turns out that
systems rigged so everyone goes to hell
but it's not really rigged it's the
point system because it deals with all
of the outcomes all of the happiness
created by your actions we live in a
very complex world so if you buy a
tomato you're supporting the pesticide
industry and you're supporting bad labor
practices and so you end up with
negative points for doing something that
you won't you didn't know about and
Chiti in that show who is indecisive and
can never figure out what choice I'm
very much a Chiti and he's still like
listen like I do look at the
consequences for everything and it still
made it hard and bad and I still ended
up in the in the bad place because
literally everyone for the last 500
years has ended up in the bad place
because of this unintended consequences
that everything we do and it's not
really we're the ones choosing it we're
the ones choosing and it's just like
clearly not a reality but at the same
time there is truth there that when you
buy a tomato when you buy a chocolate
bar you have all of the ripple effects
at that choice makes and real ripple
effects that aren't necessarily you're
going to heaven or hell but like there
are actual children in slavery my ed
mining mining the chocolate that's where
chocolate comes from right growing or
picking the cocoa there's there's slave
energy that's gone into my cellphone but
we don't necessarily have other any
other options like with a cell phone and
we don't necessarily we can't
necessarily have all of the information
to be able to make choices and even if
you do you're one person so even if you
make perfect choices no one else is
going to because it's too complex and
that's a lot of what because I am Gd I'm
like I need more information I can't
make a decision I very much can see what
we can create together which is the
consequence of our actions not so that
you have to sit there indecisive between
to buy this tomato or talk about this
tomato this one's negative 500 points
this one's positive 10,000 points that's
kind of a no-brainer but it's seen that
point system actually being able to see
okay what is in alignment with my values
and what are the consequences of this
action and then the person can choose
and when there aren't good options when
it's like okay negative 500 or negative
450 well this one's about animals and
this one's towards people and I care
more about people that animals I'll pick
the one that's gonna hurt animals
whereas we together can create okay well
if there isn't a tomato on the market
that isn't negative and isn't hurting
people we can create that together we
can create a tomato I mean it's not the
tomato it's like if you grow tomatoes in
your backyard it does not have that
consequence and so we could start a farm
that's like okay we're do we're gonna
pay farmers as well or sorry at the end
agricultural workers well or we are
going to be the agricultural workers
we're not going to use pesticides when
we do we're going to make that decision
together so that we can weigh the
trade-off and say okay well either we
just this crop gets destroyed or we use
this pesticide one time here's the
science behind this pesticide and let's
make a choice and again that wouldn't be
everyone making that choice would be the
people who are part owners in that farm
people who are using that farm to get
their tomatoes from that are part of
that democratic system not all people
everywhere little complex but um yeah I
like the idea I have really liked a good
place they also have two of my favorite
actresses I can't member named Camille
she's I just I only know her from that
show except now that she keeps tweeting
about beauty standards and
they are not okay in sin she's just
awesome and like she keeps calling out
all the beauty industry like stop
telling women to not but they need to
not age or they should sell you like
they need like this is what being a
human body is and so I really like her
now I didn't I only knew her character
on the good place before and then I'm
Kristen Bell who I do know more cuz I've
seen or interviewed more often and
watched her for a few things but I love
her personality and I also like it like
her character on the good place but that
was today's talk aspired by a show that
is of course not but that's kind of what
they're saying it's like we live in a
very complex hard society and how do
people make these choices when they
don't have the ability to make them
they're so stressed out about their own
lives their own consequences from
everything happening that they live in
that capitalistic too much information
not enough information world and I
propose we organize it we organize that
information and make it available and
where there aren't good options we make
the bad options go away
we no longer support them they don't let
her get our money and they don't exist
any longer the good options we can
support and where there aren't good
options we can create our own Thanks see
you tomorrow